<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Hector Aguilar</title>
    <subtitle>Hector Aguilar is a front-end engineer that based on Mexico City</subtitle>
    <link href="https://bitbyte.blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://bitbyte.blog" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
        <name>Hector Aldair Aguilar Hernandez</name>
    </author>
    
        <updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    
    <id>https://bitbyte.blog/</id>
        <entry>
            <title>An original title for a first blog post</title>
            <link href="https://bitbyte.blog/blog/an-original-title-for-a-first-blog-post/"/>
            <updated>2021-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <id>https://bitbyte.blog/blog/an-original-title-for-a-first-blog-post/</id>
            <content type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                <p>Hello, world! This is my first post ever made on this new site.</p>
<p>This is the place where I'm going to write about my life, my work, and my hobbies. The things that I want to save in a secure place instead of my head.</p>
<p>Why am I making this website and not using some other tool like medium?
Well, the first reason is... I don't know how to make a website so I'm making this one.</p>
<p>The second reason is that I want control over the content of my posts and something very simple.
I don't want paywalls, ads, etc. It's just a blog, not a new NTF collection.</p>
<p>Well, maybe I'll add some ads in the future. <strong>That's a bad joke</strong> please ignore it.</p>
<p>The next post will be about how I'm making this website and the resources I'm using.</p>
<p>But if you're a little impatient, you can check out this <a href="https://github.com/hectoraldairah/bitbyte-blog">Github repo</a></p>
<p>I'm using <a href="https://www.11ty.dev/">Eleventy</a> btw.</p>
<p>Quote of the day:
You need to finish your shit before you start your next one.
- IDK</p>

            ]]>
            </content>
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>Things I want to learn on 2022</title>
            <link href="https://bitbyte.blog/blog/things-i-want-to-learn-on-2022/"/>
            <updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <id>https://bitbyte.blog/blog/things-i-want-to-learn-on-2022/</id>
            <content type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                <p>It's the end of the year, and I'm starting to think about what I want to learn in 2022.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>A new programming language: I'm thinking on Clojure, Elm, or Elixir. I need to understand better the concepts of functional programming and how to use them. Maybe I'll use this expertise to apply javascript.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A new pixel art tool: I used to work with Photoshop and Adobe Flash to make pixel art animations, but I don't want to use them anymore (I can't run any Adobe App now) so I'm thinking to use <a href="https://aseprite.org/">aseprite</a> because I did some basic animation with it two years ago.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Blender: I did some 3D animations when I was like 16? on an old mini laptop that I had. It was good at the time with only 2 Gb of ram but man, the software is getting ram expensive. Maybe I can start to make some things with my new computer.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How to talk in public: Since 2019, I get the interest to do talks about tech with one cup of acid humor on it. The pandemic was a big problem here because there are no more live meetups and I just forget about it. With the online meetups, I can feel a chance to do it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Back-end: Well, maybe this is kind of huge for me. I've been doing front-end stuff for a while and my backend skills are getting pretty bad. My experience working with <a href="https://expressjs.com/es/">Express</a> and <a href="https://adonisjs.com/">Adonis</a> was pretty good, but it was simple things. I don't know anything about databases too. So, yeah. Maybe I'll buy a course from <a href="https://www.udemy.com/">Udemy</a> for it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>CSS Art: Yes, another art stuff. All the <a href="https://codepen.io/tag/css-art">beautiful CSS art that is on codepen</a> makes me want to do something similar. I'm not sure what exactly but some 3D CSS animations are on my eye.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Being fluent in Esperanto and learning more about romantic languages: Duolingo and <a href="https://lernu.net/">Lernu</a> are my best friends here.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>That's it. I don't want to write more on this post to avoid feeling bad at the end of 2022.</p>
<p>Happy 2022!</p>

            ]]>
            </content>
        </entry></feed>